What we have depicted right over here is a combustion reaction.
ما قمنا يصور على حق هنا هو رد فعل الاحتراق.
We have the hydrocarbon methane right over here.
لدينا النفط والغاز الحق الميثان أكثر من هنا.
You take that.
كنت تأخذ ذلك.
You take some molecular oxygen.
كنت تأخذ بعض الأكسجين الجزيئي.
You give them enough heat.
كنت منحهم ما يكفي من الحرارة.
And then, they are going to combust.
ومن ثم، فهي الذهاب إلى حرق.
And they're going to produce carbon dioxide, water, and then
وانهم ذاهبون لإنتاج ثاني أكسيد الكربون والماء، ومن ثم
more energy than you put in.
المزيد من الطاقة مما كنت وضعت فيه.
This is an exothermic reaction.
هذا هو تفاعل طارد للحرارة.
More energy comes out than you put in.
ويأتي المزيد من الطاقة من مما كنت وضعت فيه.
This is why fires keep spreading.
هذا هو السبب في الحرائق إبقاء نشر.
This is why combustion is used to power things.
هذا هو السبب في احتراق يستخدم لأشياء السلطة.
But that's not what we're going to focus on in this video.
ولكن هذا ليس ما نحن ذاهبون يجب التركيز عليها في هذا الفيديو.
In this video, we want to think about-- which
في هذا الفيديو، ونحن نريد التفكير about-- التي
of these components, of these molecules, what's
من هذه المكونات، من هذه الجزيئات، ما هو
being oxidized and what is being reduced?
التعرض للأكسدة و ما يجري تخفيض؟
And to do that, let's first think
وللقيام بذلك، دعونا نفكر أولا
about the oxidation states of the input atoms
حول أكسدة دول ذرات المدخلات
and the oxidation states of the outputs--
والأكسدة دول outputs--
of the different constituents of these molecules.
من مكونات مختلفة من هذه الجزيئات.
So I encourage you to now pause this video
لذلك أهيب بكم أن الآن وقفة هذا الفيديو
and try to figure that out on your own.
ومحاولة لمعرفة هذا بنفسك.
So I'm assuming you've given a go at it.
لذلك أفترض أنك قمت نظرا الذهاب في ذلك.
Now, let's work through this together.
الآن، دعونا نعمل من خلال هذا معا.
Let's first think about the methane.
دعونا نفكر أولا عن الميثان.
And I have a bunch of electronegativities here based
ولدي مجموعة من كهربية مقرها هنا
on the Pauling scale listed out here,
على مقياس بولينغ المدرجة هنا،
but let's just visualize methane.
ولكن دعونا فقط تصور الميثان.
Methane is a carbon bonded to 4 hydrogens.
الميثان هو الكربون المستعبدين من 4 الهيدروجين.
In our oxidation state world-- even though, this, in reality,
في منطقتنا world-- حالة الأكسدة على الرغم من هذا، في الواقع،
is a covalent bond-- we pretend like they're
هو التساهمية bond-- نحن نتظاهر وكأنهم
hypothetically ionic bonds.
الرابطة الأيونية نظريا.
So we have to give the electron pair to one of the parties
لذلك لدينا لإعطاء الإلكترون الزوج إلى أحد الطرفين
to the bond.
إلى السندات.
If we look between carbon and hydrogen,
إذا نظرنا بين الكربون والهيدروجين،
carbon is more electronegative than hydrogen.
الكربون هو أكثر كهربية من الهيدروجين.
So we will assume that carbon will be hogging the electrons
لذلك فإننا نفترض أن الكربون سيتم القص الإلكترونات
and that hydrogen will be giving away the electrons.
وأن الهيدروجين سيكون التخلي عن الإلكترونات.
So carbon's going to take-- in this hypothetical world--
لذا الكربون الذهاب الى take-- في هذا world-- افتراضية
hypothetically take an electron from each of these hydrogens.
نظريا اتخاذ إلكترون من كل هذه هيدروجين.
It is going to have an oxidation state of negative 4,
انها ستكون لدينا حالة الأكسدة سلبية 4،
an electron from each of 4 hydrogens.
إلكترون من كل من 4 الهيدروجين.
Negative 4.
سلبي 4.
And once again, we write the sign after the number
ومرة أخرى، ونحن نكتب علامة بعد الرقم
probably so that we don't get these confused with exponents.
ربما حتى لم نحصل على هذه الخلط بينه وبين الأسس.
Now, let's think about the hydrogens.
الآن، دعونا نفكر حول هيدروجين.
Each of those hydrogens is having--
كل من هذه الهيدروجين هو having--
in this hypothetical world-- an electron taken away from it.
في هذا world-- افتراضية الإلكترون تؤخذ بعيدا عن ذلك.
We could say it has an oxidation state of plus 1, which
يمكن أن نقول أنه يحتوي على الدولة أكسدة زائد 1، التي
we could write as 1 plus.
نحن يمكن أن يكتب ك 1 زائد.
Or we could just write a positive right
أو يمكننا فقط إرسال حق إيجابي
over here-- a plus sign.
على here-- علامة زائد.